# WELLING R. GUZMAN CABRERA

Santiago, Dominican Republic hire@wellingguzman.com • https://wellingguzman.com

## **PROFILE**

Software Engineer with several years of experience developing and designing complex applications and databases architecture using different technologies and platforms. I have solid understanding of the web, relational databases and servers.

Interested in working with REST APIs, Web API, accessability, security, cloud computing, high availability, reliability, complex applications, micro-services, infrastructure, servers and networking.

#### **SKILLS**

- Web Development
- Desktop Development
- RDBMS/Relational Database
- Database Architecture
- Restful APIs
- Linux/Unix Servers
- Docker, Vagrant
- HTTP
- TCP/IP
- OAuth

- PHP 5/7
- JavaScript/Node.js
- HTML
- CSS/Sass/Less
- Objective-C
- C/C++
- Java, Swing
- Visual FoxPro
- Ruby/Sinatra
- Python/PyGame

- Load Balancing
- SQL, MySQL, SQL Server, DBF
- AWS: S3, CloudFront, Aurora
- Backbone.js, jQuery
- WordPress: Plugins, Themes
- Zend, Laravel, Symfony, Slim
- RabbitMQ/Work Queue
- Redis/Memcached/MongoDB
- Socket.io/WebSockets
- Stripe/Mailchimp

- Git
- Gulp/Grunt
- Apache/NGINX
- PHPUnit
- Travis CI
- Composer
- Photoshop
- Responsive Web Design
- SCIM
- Community Support

## **EXPERIENCE**

## Software Engineer & Lead Development

Directus (Remote)

Aug 2014 - Present

- Major contributor to Directus 6, Directus API and Directus Software as a Service (SaaS) Application.
- Contributions include creating user interfaces, web application performance, API improvements, database optimization, security and customer/community support.
- Led the restructuring of the project's API into a REST architecture independent from the web application and the support multi-tenant environment, using S.O.L.I.D. principles, layered architecture, pipeline pattern, and modular components.

#### Software Engineer and Consultant (Independent Contractor)

Remote

Apr 2003 - Present

 Advised and developed solutions for numerous platforms that involved managing assets (image, audio and video), software for private school, online payment processing, serverless/cloud solution, Software as a Service (SaaS) and real state properties.

## **Full-Stack Software Engineer**

EQUIMECA, SRL

Jan 2007 - Apr 2015

- Learned new programming languages to implement and improve existing in-house software by eliminating
  inconsistent processing, inadequate interfaces, merging data issues, incorrect data handling, incorrect
  implementation of business requirements and adding important internal and governmental-required features.
- Developed and redesigned accounting software for this company in the pharmaceutical industry.
- Provided computer training to Human Resources, accounting, warehouse and office personnel which included familiarizing them with in-house software, company available tools and resources.

### **Technical Support**

EQUIMECA, SRL

Sep 2004 - Dec 2006

- Performed computer maintenance and monitoring to maintain an optimal performance of computer systems, network and applications.
- Assisted in the implementation of a new adequate computer system and network to sustain the work load of a growing company

#### **EDUCATION**

2004 - 2010